

CONTACT

- +62 812 2464 1242
- Bandung, Indonesia
- in @feryyp
- portfolio
- github.com/daefery

EXPERTISE

HARD SKILLS

Html, API Design, Javascript,
PHP, Css, React, NextJs, Ui Ux,
Backend, Python Django, Git,
Tdd, Restful, SQL, CI/CD,
Wordpress, Database, Testing,
Troubleshooting, JQuery,
Flutter

SOFT SKILLS

Creativity, Curiosity,
Collaborative, Innovative,
Leadership, Flexibility,
Adaptability, Responsible

INTEREST





Movie

Traveling



Sports

de Game

FERY YUNDARA PUTERA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Highly-skilled software development professional bringing more than 8 years in software design and problem solver. Advanced knowledge of website development, UI/UX designer and project management. Skilled at technical leadership, communication and presentations. Experienced in full project life-cycle using Agile and SCRUM.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

JUN 2018 - PRESENT

Solve Education!, INDONESIA

- Supported game client by provide them endpoints.
- Minimized web issue by implementing end-to-end testing with automation (Selenium).
- Minimized error code by implementing unit test for backend and frontend including code coverage.
- Minimized deployment issue by implementing CI/CD process.
- Achieved clear project description and requirement by creating technical and project requirement project document.

BACKEND DEVELOPER

AUG 2016 - JUN 2018

Xtremax, SINGAPORE & INDONESIA

- · Maintained three projects.
- Gained CRM Sitefinity certificate and other training by taking the exam of Sitefinity.
- Achieved a project build with MVC .NET and Javascript.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

JAN 2015 - JUL 2016

Elephant Talk (Pareteum), SPAIN & INDONESIA

- Gained knowledge about telco system by joined the intense training.
- Converted many business operation into micro services technically on code base.
- Minimized issue reported by implementing clean code, integration test and unit testing.
- Achieved two big web application projects implemented using Angular JS and C#.
- Gained experience on C# microservice process.

.NET DEVELOPER

JAN 2014 - JAN 2015

PT. Suzuki Indomobil Motor, INDONESIA

- Finished .NET project and installed on every main branch office.
- Application interface improved by implemented Angular JS framework.
- Completed technical documentation of the project.

CERTIFICATE & TRAINING

TRAINING

 TDD Methodology 2021

 Project Management 2020

2020 Website Development

Process

2017 • Penetration Test

 Sharepoint 2017

Development

2015 Telco System Workflow

• Enterprise System 2013

Development

· Softskill, Ethic. 2013

Commtment and

Career Roadmap

CERTIFICATE

 Professional Academy 2021

Digital Talent

Scholarship

 Certified Sitefinity 2016

Developer

INTERNSHIP PROJECT

Faxtor Web App 2019

Frontend Developer - Faxtor

Tech: Angular JS, Material UI, SASS

Dompu Pariwisata 2019

Mobile Developer - Dompu

Tech: React Native. Native Base

Elim Medical Center 2013

Fullstack Developer, Aplysit

Tech: PHP Native Customize Framework

EDUCATION

BINA NUSANTARA UNIVERSITY JUL 2015 - JUL 2017

JAKARTA, INDONESIA

Bachelor of Information Systems

- Honors: (GPA: 3.51/4.0)
- Final Project: Web App: Supply Chain Management

TELKOM UNIVERSITY

SEP 2010 - SEP 2013

BANDUNG, INDONESIA

Associate degree of Computer Engineering in Network Programming

- Honors: (GPA: 3.45/4.0)
- Final Project: Web App: Social Media Traffic AND Weather Location

PROJECTS

Solve Employment

JAN 2022 - PRESENT

Frontend Developer - Solve Education!

Tech : React JS. JEST. Semantic UI. SASS. Lumen

Ed The Bot Website

JAN 2022 - PRESENT

Frontend Developer - Solve Education! Tech : React JS, JEST, Semantic UI, SASS, Lumen

Localizy JUN 2018 - PRESENT

Fullstack Developer - Solve Education!

Tech: React JS, Selenium, Semantic UI, SASS, Lumen

JUN 2018 - PRESENT Content+

Frontend Developer - Solve Education!

Tech: React JS, Selenium, Semantic UI, SASS, Django

Learnalytics JUN 2018 - PRESENT

Fullstack Developer - Solve Education!

Tech: React JS, Selenium, Semantic UI, Laravel

Weekly Challenge Web

JUN 2018 - PRESENT

Frontend Developer - Solve Education!

Tech : React JS, JEST, Semantic UI, SASS, Lumen

JUN 2018 - PRESENT

Fullstack Developer - Solve Education!

Tech: Django, Semantic UI

ONESERVICE Web Portal JAN 2016 - JUN 2018

Fullstack Developer - Xtremax

Tech:.NET MVC

Supreme Court Singapore

JAN 2018 - JUN 2018

Fullstack Developer - Xtremax

Tech:.NET MVC

ET Self Care & CSR

JAN 2015 - JAN 2016

JAN 2015 - JAN 2016

Frontend Developer - Elephant Talk Tech: Angular JS, SASS, .NET MVC

ET Mobile Number Portability

Backend Developer - Elephant Talk

Tech:.NET, C#

SDMS Suzuki JAN 2014 - DEC 2014

Fullstack Developer - PT Suzuki Indomobil Motor

Tech:.NET MVC, C#